<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ed Freyfogle</title>
    <description>Ed Freyfogle&#39;s blog
</description>
    <link>http://freyfogle.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://freyfogle.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 14:26:27 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 14:26:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sommerferien</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the great joys of having &lt;a href=&quot;https://geocoder.opencagedata.com&quot;&gt;a lifestyle business&lt;/a&gt; is … the lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such I recently booked tickets for five weeks of summer break. The kids
and I - my wife unfortunately has to work the first few weeks - will be in &lt;a href=&quot;https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heilbad_Heiligenstadt&quot;&gt;Heiligenstadt, Thüringen&lt;/a&gt; all of August. No plans, just go for hikes in the woods and swimming. We’ll grill
some bratwurst. If you’re around and want to swing by and say
hello - we’re a ten minute walk from the train station - let me know. Also,
the various &lt;a href=&quot;https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mittelpunkt_Deutschlands&quot;&gt;Mittelpunkte Deutschlands&lt;/a&gt; are all nearby, so there’s plenty to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May try to day trip it out to the old haunts in Weimar …&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:19:47 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/1466377094/ab-nach-thueringen</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/1466377094/ab-nach-thueringen</guid>
        
        
        <category>bestsummerever,</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It is done, the blog is moved</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After much procrastination I’ve finally moved the blog off of tumblr. I’m
now &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/github-pages/&quot;&gt;making the site with jekyll and hosting on github pages&lt;/a&gt;. I’m liking it much more, and used it as a chance to finally
make a very simple “about me” page which you can now find on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freyfogle.com&quot;&gt;freyfogle.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is oddly conceptually similar to the “jake” system we built at yahoo
about 15 years ago, so I feel right at home. Free hosting from github is ace.
The biggest difficulty was importing all the old posts from tumblr.
There is a migration tool, but I found it didn’t work, I think the underlying
format of tumblr’s API has changed. Anyway, I had to write my own little adhoc
tool which was easy enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest regret is not having made this move much sooner. Next up is to move
the &lt;a href=&quot;http://geomobldn.org&quot;&gt;#geomob&lt;/a&gt; blog off of tumblr and make that look a
bit less adhoc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway the path is now cleared for a onslaught of blogging. There is much
to tell as a few new projects are brewing.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 12:07:36 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/1465380424/it-is-done</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/1465380424/it-is-done</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Jornadas SIG Libre #siglibre10 talk</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I’m in Girona speaking at the 10th &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sigte.udg.edu/jornadassiglibre/&quot;&gt;Jornadas SIG Libre&lt;/a&gt;, the main geo free and opensource software event in Spain. Many thanks to the organizers for putting together the event and allowing me to speak.
It was my first time to Girona, which is shameful given how close it is to Barcelona (40min by high speed train), and the city is beautiful. Likewise the university, and in fact the conference was held in an old monestary. Here’s a great shot of me by twitter user &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/inspide_me/status/735037022230982656&quot;&gt;@inspide_me&lt;/a&gt; speaking in this amazing venue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;figure data-orig-width=&quot;600&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;1067&quot; class=&quot;tmblr-full&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img data-orig-width=&quot;600&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;1067&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/540.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My talk focused on some of the trends I’ve seen in running &lt;a href=&quot;http://geomobldn.org/&quot;&gt;#geomob&lt;/a&gt; over the last years. The obvious point is that with the rise of smart phones geo and location based services have now become the norm in everyone’s life - rich and poor, young and old. As a consequence, the key differentiatior of success and failure is increasingly NOT technical perfection and feature completeness, but rather usability. Simple wins, a lesson it is often easy for developers to forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My talk is below, let me know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;speakerdeck-embed&quot; data-id=&quot;8fa76f07490e41eb9b03130ccfb0d855&quot; data-ratio=&quot;1.33333333333333&quot; src=&quot;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 14:22:58 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/144851440100/my-jornadas-sig-libre-siglibre10-talk</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/144851440100/my-jornadas-sig-libre-siglibre10-talk</guid>
        
        
        <category>events,</category>
        
        <category>speaking,</category>
        
        <category>jornadasSIGlibre,</category>
        
        <category>siglibre10</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving the blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to move this blog off of tumblr and onto something I control more directly, probably also with a better front page on freyfogle.com that gives a bit more background about me and what I’m up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Partially I’m frustrated with tumblr’s tools (particularly the way it tries to “help” with formatting), partially I’m worried about tumblr’s future as parent-company yahoo sells, but most of all I want to create a better first impression for my digital identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does anyone have any recommendations (do not say wordpress, I hate wordpress). Right now I’m leaning toward &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; as it is plain text, which I can relate to.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 19:24:36 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/143741854375/moving-the-blog</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/143741854375/moving-the-blog</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thoughts on the UK Euro referendum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks back, on the 21st of Februrary to be exact, the UK government announced there will be a referendum about leaving the EU. Though I no longer live in the UK, I write these thoughts on the referendum as an EU citizen who spent the last 10 years living there, my two children were born there, and a few years ago my wife got UK citizenship.  While in the UK I (with another non-UK EU citizen) started a company that received foreign investment, employed and trained about 60 people (over the course of the 10 years, not all at once), and built a small, but global, business. I have paid my fair share of tax - and far more than any person’s fair share of rent - in the UK, I experienced the pleasure and pain of the NHS, I celebrated the Queen’s jubilee, I am an investor in about 10 different UK businesses, etc. I of course don’t have the chance to vote in the referendum, but nevertheless wanted to briefly express my view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the frustrations with the discussion around a big decision like the referendum (or the Scottish referendum the year before, or the discussion about Catalan independence here in Barcelona) is that both sides produce all sorts of numbers to argue their case, and it is utterly impossible for the layman to know what to believe. There is endless discussion and debates about various “facts”, most of it entirely unprovable. For the record, I do believe leaving the EU would be bad for the UK economically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me though, the date of the announcement of the referendum served as a great reminder of why we need the EU and why you should vote to stay in. February 23, 2016 was the 100th anniversary of the start of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Verdun&quot;&gt;battle of Verdun&lt;/a&gt;, one of the most brutal battles in human history, with close to a million casualties. In the UK, Verdun, because the battle featured Germans versus French, is overshadowed &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_the_Somme&quot;&gt;by the Somme&lt;/a&gt;, as a metaphore for senseless loss of life. Historians no doubt have a many a drunked argument about which was worse, but no doubt they were all horrific, as were many, many other battles in which Europeans killed other Europeans. I spent part of my childhood in Germany, growing up not that far away, and had the chance to visit Verdun a few times. If you can you should go, there is no other way to comprehend the utter scale of it. Even today huge stretches are still fenced off as they are too full of bombs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/verdun.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cathedral like building in this picture is one of many memorials in Verdun. It is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Douaumont_Ossuary&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Beinhaus von Douaumont&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, it contains the remains of 130,000 people. Think about that for a sec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re very fortunate that most modern Europeans never had to live through a catastrophic war, and we forget that it used to be totally normal for there to be a massive war between European countries once a generation. Or that the country I now live in, Spain, was a dictatorship in living memory, and indeed most of eastern Europe much more recently than that.
That is why we need the EU, and why we all need to be in it and continually working to improve it. So we don’t drift apart and fight, but rather so we work together to improve. The temptation to slide back into “us vs. them” thinking is always there - as we see most recently with Trump in the US, or many other examples. Working together is hard work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people, especially in the UK - but by no means only there, like to criticize the EU. Fair enough, that is their right. But we also shouldn’t forget what amazing progress has been made only in the last 30 years. Not only should we not forget it, we should celebrate it wildly, especially when we look at where we were only 100 years ago. More needs to be done to make the democracy in the EU more transparent, and probably many of the current systems and ways of working will need to change. The same was the case when the US started, and indeed any participatory government is always going to be a work in progress. So let’s do that work. But let’s not drift apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have the chance to vote in the referendum, please vote to stay. Let’s work together to create the EU we want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW - if you want to learn more about Verdun and WWI in general I highly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dancarlin.com/hardcore-history-series/&quot;&gt;Dan Carlin’s Hard Core History podcasts on the topic&lt;/a&gt;. They have been a great treat for me over the last few weeks.
Foto by &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=47593127&quot;&gt;Leon petrosyan - Own work, CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks Leon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 16:29:51 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/142627086455/thoughts-on-the-uk-euro-referendum</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/142627086455/thoughts-on-the-uk-euro-referendum</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Speaking at Jornadas SIG libre</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m delighted to announce I’ve been invited to speak at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sigte.udg.edu/jornadassiglibre/&quot;&gt;Jornadas SIG libre conference&lt;/a&gt; in Girona at the end of May. The event is the Spanish FOSS4G, the main conference about free and open source geospatial software.
I’m starting to think about what I might have to say that would be relevant to the audience, if you have any suggestions please let me know. Right now I’m thinking I’ll primarily focus on the trends I’ve seen in running &lt;a href=&quot;http://geomobldn.org/&quot;&gt;#geomob&lt;/a&gt; over the last six years, the lessons learned in running the &lt;a href=&quot;https://geocoder.opencagedata.com/&quot;&gt;OpenCage Geocoder&lt;/a&gt;, and  thoughts on investing in geo startups like &lt;a href=&quot;http://what3words.com/&quot;&gt;What3Words&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.splash-maps.com/&quot;&gt;SplashMaps&lt;/a&gt;.  
It should be a great event, and I’m looking forward to it as I’ve never been to Girona which everyone says is great. The language of the conference is Spanish, but I think to make any sort of meaningful presentation my talk will have to be in English.
Final thing: if geo events are your thing &lt;a href=&quot;http://geomobldn.org/post/139352132255/see-you-on-the-15th-of-march&quot;&gt;the next #geomob is on 15th of March&lt;/a&gt;, come along if you’re in London.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 11:55:45 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/139962599485/speaking-at-jornadas-sig-libre</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/139962599485/speaking-at-jornadas-sig-libre</guid>
        
        
        <category>jornadasSIGlibre,</category>
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Joining the board of MyBuilder</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last months many people have gotten in touch asking what I’m up to professionally since leaving Lokku. I’m exploring a number of different things, one that I’m pleased to now be able to announce is joining the board of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mybuilder.com/&quot;&gt;MyBuilder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;figure data-orig-width=&quot;1135&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;733&quot; class=&quot;tmblr-full&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img data-orig-width=&quot;1135&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;733&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/540.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those unfamiliar with the service, MyBuilder is a UK based marketplace where homeowners can find quality tradesmen. Whether you need a plumber, want to redo the kitchen, put solar panels on the roof, or whatever, MyBuilder helps you quickly and easily find and compare reputable tradesmen to get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve known the MyBuilder team for many years, in some ways the story is not unlike my own - an American founder who came to the UK and started a company around 2005. They are based in Clerkenwell, just as we were. 
Like our own journey with Lokku, it has been one of perseverance. Ryan Notz, the CEO and founder, and his team have tenaciously grown the business over the years. One thing that has really impressed me, and the reason I decided to get involved, is that they are focused on truly helping the homeowner solve the problem of repairing their home. What I mean is, many players in this space just flog leads out to anyone with an email address who is willing to buy them. MyBuilder takes a much deeper, more comprehensive approach. First, tradesmen who want to join the marketplace undergo an identity check AND a thorough test of their skills for the specific category they are interested in. They can not just say “I’m happy to do plumbing, wiring, masonry, gas fitting, really whatever anyone will pay me to do”. Secondly, the job is not simply spammed out to any and every tradesmen. If you want your kitchen redone that’s a big task with lots of decision to be made, the last thing you want to do is to first have to sift through hundreds of possible tradesmen. Instead, what you want is a short list of a handful of reputable, qualified, and available contractors, and that is exactly what MyBuilder provides. As you would expect, you can see reviews and ratings of their past work. It’s an approach that helps the homeowner solve the real task, not just a quick way to sell a lead, which is what many of MyBuilder’s competitors (who have come and gone over the years) have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equally important to Ryan and the management team though is creating a great culture within the team. &lt;a href=&quot;http://careers.mybuilder.com/&quot;&gt;They are hiring for a bunch of roles&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to work with great people building a great service, one that helps thousands of consumers and tradesmen every month, I can not think of a better company for you to join. The spirit of pride in the service is noticeable in everyone you talk with, and just like the tradesmen they aim to serve, there is a great sense of craftsmanship in the product side of the business. If you are interested in a product or tech role, have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.mybuilder.com/&quot;&gt;their tech blog&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mybuilder/&quot;&gt;code they have open-sourced&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This thoughtful approach is not always quick, but it is solid and it is paying off. The business is thriving. 2015 was a record year, and 2016 should be even better. More and more tradesmen are signing up, and the percentage of jobs posted by repeat users of the service is quite simply amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of that isn’t to say there are not challenges ahead for MyBuilder. The path from start-up to scale-up, from 5 team members to 50+, and then 200+, is not a simple one. Likewise, providing a high quality service raises customer expectations, and those expectations need to be continually met and exceeded. As MyBuilder moves out of the start-up phase of life and increasingly becomes a household name, I’m hopeful my own experiences and perspective can help on their journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 15:19:21 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/139847718265/joining-the-board-of-mybuilder</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/139847718265/joining-the-board-of-mybuilder</guid>
        
        
        <category>mybuilder</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>co-working life</title>
        <description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;figure data-orig-width=&quot;720&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;960&quot; class=&quot;tmblr-full&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img data-orig-width=&quot;720&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;960&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/540.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend was kind enough to invite me along to visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.betahaus.es/&quot;&gt;Betahaus Barcelona&lt;/a&gt; for a day this week. Unbeknownst to me they snapped this pic of me hard at work and are now using it on their FB feed. Might this be the big break that finally lands me in the pages of Monocle?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 22:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/139617318635/co-working-life</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/139617318635/co-working-life</guid>
        
        
        <category>betahaus,</category>
        
        <category>workinghardorhardlyworking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Steady progress on mapping the new neighborhood</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freyfogle.com/post/138272982085/goals-for-2016&quot;&gt;my goals for 2016&lt;/a&gt; was to map the new neighbourhood as a way to get to know what is where. I’m making slow but steady progress, and it’s been a good refresh. Years of living in central London, which is mapped in amazing detail, made it hard to find new things to map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;figure data-orig-width=&quot;1670&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;1038&quot; class=&quot;tmblr-full&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img data-orig-width=&quot;1670&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;1038&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/540.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been focusing on addresses mainly, though have also found and corrected several bad roads, missing names of parks, etc. My technique has mainly been pen and paper and then edit on the desktop, though in the last few days I’ve been experimenting with using &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Go_Map!!&quot;&gt;the Go Map!! app&lt;/a&gt; on my iphone. It’s ok for adding addresses, though the limited screen space makes it hard to do much more. A very challenging usability problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway I should have the addresses for my main radius of action done in a few weeks, and am debating what to then focus on. It’s been a fun experiment and helped me learn the new neighbourhood. I recommend it if you move somewhere new.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 13:43:16 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/139479274255/steady-progress-on-mapping-the-new-neighborhood</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/139479274255/steady-progress-on-mapping-the-new-neighborhood</guid>
        
        
        <category>openstreetmap</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interviewed by Geospatial Training Español</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It was my pleasure to recently do &lt;a href=&quot;http://geospatialtraininges.com/2016/02/08/opencagegeocoder-un-geocodificador-sencillo-practico-y-economico/&quot;&gt;an interview with the Geospatial Training Services Español blog&lt;/a&gt;, which is widely read in the Spanish geo industry. I talk a bit about what we are up to with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://geocoder.opencagedata.com/&quot;&gt;OpenCage geocoder&lt;/a&gt; and my impressions of Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I can’t claim that I was able to do the interview in Spanish. Quizás el próximo año?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/asantosestevez&quot;&gt;Alberto Santos&lt;/a&gt; for the opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 11:13:35 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/138980702260/interviewed-by-geospatial-training-español</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/138980702260/interviewed-by-geospatial-training-español</guid>
        
        
        <category>interview</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
