<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ed Freyfogle</title>
    <description>Ed Freyfogle&#39;s blog
</description>
    <link>http://freyfogle.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://freyfogle.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 17:06:56 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 17:06:56 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving to Barcelona</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So yesterday was the EU referendum in the UK and the result was in favour of leaving. The result saddens me, I &lt;a href=&quot;/post/142627086455/thoughts-on-the-uk-euro-referendum&quot;&gt;laid out my opinion in a post&lt;/a&gt; a few months ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two immediate observations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Due to the advisory, non-legally binding nature of the referendum, and the fact that nothing comparable to this has ever happened before, there is still so much uncertainty over what this means for Britain (and areas within like Scotland) and Europe. There is already speculation of a re-vote (hard to see that happening) or that it will never be implemented. No one can say. It’s the very uncertainty that makes it so brutal. Let’s all hope the pessimistic predictions are wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Whatever happens, many of my non-British (ie immigrant) friends in London - of which I had many as London was so cosmopolitan - have shared (personally or publicly via social media) that the campaign showed them an ugly side to Britain. That they feel less welcome, in some cases actually scared.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it is not the intention of the vast majority of the British people, but as an outsider, a post-Brexit Britain definitely seems less welcoming. Every single interview with out voters quickly turns to the topic of immigration, and how they feel there is too much of it, too many of “them”. As one of “them” (I know, I know “we don’t mean people like you”), that doesn’t feel great. Nationalism and xenophobia are ugly things, and my fear is that this result normalizes such views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I offer this post to my EU friends in London, especially those in the tech sector, who are perhaps now contemplating a move, for whatever your reasons. It’s my perspective on the pros and cons of our post-London life in Barcelona. Your milage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR - come on in, the water’s fine. It’s not London and that’s why it’s great. The tech scene is smaller, and that’s great too.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Background: my family and I left London just over a year ago, and probably for some of the same reasons that lead people to vote out. The quality of life in London was just not good, especially with two young children. I had hoped to convince my wife we should move to Berlin, we went and tried it out &lt;a href=&quot;/post/96569192005/berlin-and-bestsummerever&quot;&gt;for two months in the summer of 2014&lt;/a&gt;, but she eventually was offered a great job in Barcelona, and in May 2015 we moved here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived speaking no Spanish or Catalan. I had been to Spain many times in the past, though mainly to the Basque region, and only three times to Barcelona - all just the usual 2-3 day tourist visits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My impressions one year in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pros:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First up, the weather is unbeatable, especially when you come from London. You very quickly forget that there is such a thing as a non-sunny day. I’m outside much, much more than I ever was in London.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The weather is just one piece of an overall massive improvement in quality of life. In London everything was expensive and a slog, here it is affordable and easy. The flat we rent is twice the size of our place in London and costs much less. And has much better tenant rights. I grill on my terrace looking out on the Mediterranean. The beach is not far, nor is nice hiking in the hills above the city. Restaurants are cheap and amazing (though we don’t quite have the culinary diversity of London).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The infrastructure. The metro works well and is very cheap, as are cabs. Two streets down from our place is a great public library. There are fantastic museums and parks. In the northern European media (UK, German) Spain is portrayed as some third-world country with dogs wandering in the street. The reality is the infrastructure here is significantly superior to London. My only suggestions for how the city could improve is more bike lanes and allow services like uber. When I feel like going back to London, I do. It’s simple. The airport is a cheap 15 minute cab ride away (not an expensive, hour-long train ride). There are cheap direct flights anywhere in Europe. Several times I’ve taken the kids to school, gone on to the airport and been in London or Berlin for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The city feels very international, but also very much has a unique culture. The huge numbers of tourists, the dual Spanish/Catalan culture, and the many expats give the city a great vibe. It is not London, no place is - you do not feel like you’re in the capital of the world, but there is a dynamic and international vibe. Everyone speaks two or three or more languages. Incidentally I have heard this is one of the big differences with between Barcelona and arch-rival Madrid. I have only visited, but am told Madrid feels very Spanish, not global. Barcelona feels global.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On a related note there are tons of international schools. And compared to UK school fees they are very affordable. In all of London there was one German school, here there are three! And many mixed language kindergartens. Of course there are also free public schools in Catalan and I know some foreigners who send their children there and are not at all unhappy. Whereas in London I once had someone tell me to speak English when I spoke German to my son here it is very normal that everyone is doing whatever their thing is. &lt;a href=&quot;/post/124564768755/life-in-a-polylingual-society&quot;&gt;It is polylingual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For foreigners the tax situation is good. If you come to Spain permanently for the first time for a job you can get a special tax status so that you pay tax only on your income, not on worldwide assets. I still have the pain of US tax, but for EU citizens that can be a phenomenal deal.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is a growing tech scene. It is much smaller than London. In some ways it reminds me of London in 2006, though without the advantage of hosting the European headquarters of many of the big global players. But there are many talented people here, especially developers, that want to build things. There are excellent co-working spaces. Just like flats, offices are cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is a definite language / cultural barrier. I have found it a real challenge to engage with non-expats. The burden is on me of course to learn the language, but the dual Spanish /Catalan situation does not help. Nor does the fact that most people speak good enough English and are happy to use it. No one wants to suffer through my tourist Spanish, nor can I blame them. I’ve had Catalan people tell me they prefer to speak English with me rather than Spanish. But language is only one issue. I’ve also had native Spanish speakers from Latin America tell me they find it very difficult as well though. The Catalans are their own society and very family oriented. They have typically lived here since birth and have their own world of friends that they have known since primary school. Everyone says hello and is polite and friendly, but they are not sitting around waiting for a newcomer to arrive so they can invite you over. It’s very unlikely they will ever invite you over. My experience is you will have to work very hard to befriend a local. Happily the expats are the opposite. Everyone is delighted to meet you and hear your story and help. Unfortunately this means that after a year here almost all of my friends and acquaintances are expats. It’s just so much easier. In that regard Barcelona still feels much more foreign than London ever did. But just to clarify, despite arriving with no Spanish I have never had a problem getting stuff done or getting around. People are always helpful, especially if you’re polite and friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The flip side of the low cost of living is that there are almost no high paying jobs. You need to either luck into a great situation or create your own job. Most expats I meet here are either already wealthy or effectively doing a northern European (or global) job from Barcelona. I’ve met several people who have virtual jobs - clients have no idea they are not in their home country. They travel back once a month or as needed. If you have a job that is location independent, or are just setting something up, the low cost of living of Barcelona is great. If you want to just move here and find a job, it will be tough.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is a tech scene, but it is still working to hit critical mass. Getting seed funding is too complex, I’ve invested in one Spanish company, the process was much slower and more bureaucratic (the notary system is INSANE rent seeking) than it would have been in London, and, like most EU countries, Spain would greatly benefit from an equivalent to the UK’s SEIS tax regime to encourage investment. Most tech events I’ve been to are “tech”, not focused on a specific technology or domain, so too generic. There aren’t yet enough role models or success stories, though that too is slowly changing. Anyway there is still tons of space to help define the scene here. I’m working on doing my small piece to change that by starting a domain specific event about messaging with a similar format to &lt;a href=&quot;http://geomobldn.org&quot;&gt;#geomob&lt;/a&gt;, the event I run in London. Our first event will be in September, I should have the details up this week.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While in Northern Europe the winter can be a real drag here it is summer that is tough. It gets very hot. In August you basically need to go away as everything closes. &lt;a href=&quot;/post/1466377094/ab-nach-thueringen&quot;&gt;We’ll be in Thüringen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is bureaucracy to suffer through when you arrive. Getting registered, etc. It was a total pain in the ass, it is hard to get the overview and there is really stupid petty stuff like you can’t pay the nominal processing fee on the same day so have to physically come back again. Everyone in Spain agrees this is the case. It really makes me wonder why they didn’t use the crisis as a chance to re-invent things. The UK has done so well at digitizing government with gov.uk. Spain is probably 10-15 years behind that. In general digitisation is still just starting here. E-commerce is just starting. People want to talk, not use a website (though they LOVE whatsapp). Anyway, the bureaucracy sucks but there are companies you can pay to help you. If you are used to the insane costs of professional services in London, they are much cheaper (and typically more responsive!). But once you are set up it is done.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, this post is getting too long, I realize now I’ve wanted to write about my impressions of BCN for a while. Overall if I could magically move to Berlin I still probably would, just because I’d prefer to live in Germany. But life in Barcelona is good and I don’t miss London at all, not least as it’s so easy to go back and visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me close by saying, please come. First to visit, we’ll eat dinner and drink wine on the terrace, and then permanently. Brexit will cause a decade of suffering. Meanwhile here we thrive in a diverse society with a great quality of life. There is great stuff happening here, and together we can make it even better.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 14:18:53 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/1466857133/moving-to-barcelona</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/1466857133/moving-to-barcelona</guid>
        
        
        <category>barcelona,</category>
        
        <category>expatlife,</category>
        
        <category>postbrexit</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sommerferien</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the great joys of having &lt;a href=&quot;https://geocoder.opencagedata.com&quot;&gt;a lifestyle business&lt;/a&gt; is … the lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such I recently booked tickets for five weeks of summer break. The kids
and I - my wife unfortunately has to work the first few weeks - will be in &lt;a href=&quot;https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heilbad_Heiligenstadt&quot;&gt;Heiligenstadt, Thüringen&lt;/a&gt; all of August. No plans, just go for hikes in the woods and swimming. We’ll grill
some bratwurst. If you’re around and want to swing by and say
hello - we’re a ten minute walk from the train station - let me know. Also,
the various &lt;a href=&quot;https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mittelpunkt_Deutschlands&quot;&gt;Mittelpunkte Deutschlands&lt;/a&gt; are all nearby, so there’s plenty to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May try to day trip it out to the old haunts in Weimar …&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:19:47 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/1466377094/ab-nach-thueringen</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/1466377094/ab-nach-thueringen</guid>
        
        
        <category>bestsummerever,</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It is done, the blog is moved</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After much procrastination I’ve finally moved the blog off of tumblr. I’m
now &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/github-pages/&quot;&gt;making the site with jekyll and hosting on github pages&lt;/a&gt;. I’m liking it much more, and used it as a chance to finally
make a very simple “about me” page which you can now find on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freyfogle.com&quot;&gt;freyfogle.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is oddly conceptually similar to the “jake” system we built at yahoo
about 15 years ago, so I feel right at home. Free hosting from github is ace.
The biggest difficulty was importing all the old posts from tumblr.
There is a migration tool, but I found it didn’t work, I think the underlying
format of tumblr’s API has changed. Anyway, I had to write my own little adhoc
tool which was easy enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest regret is not having made this move much sooner. Next up is to move
the &lt;a href=&quot;http://geomobldn.org&quot;&gt;#geomob&lt;/a&gt; blog off of tumblr and make that look a
bit less adhoc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway the path is now cleared for a onslaught of blogging. There is much
to tell as a few new projects are brewing.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 12:07:36 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/1465380424/it-is-done</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/1465380424/it-is-done</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Jornadas SIG Libre #siglibre10 talk</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I’m in Girona speaking at the 10th &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sigte.udg.edu/jornadassiglibre/&quot;&gt;Jornadas SIG Libre&lt;/a&gt;, the main geo free and opensource software event in Spain. Many thanks to the organizers for putting together the event and allowing me to speak.
It was my first time to Girona, which is shameful given how close it is to Barcelona (40min by high speed train), and the city is beautiful. Likewise the university, and in fact the conference was held in an old monestary. Here’s a great shot of me by twitter user &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/inspide_me/status/735037022230982656&quot;&gt;@inspide_me&lt;/a&gt; speaking in this amazing venue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;figure data-orig-width=&quot;600&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;1067&quot; class=&quot;tmblr-full&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img data-orig-width=&quot;600&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;1067&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/540.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My talk focused on some of the trends I’ve seen in running &lt;a href=&quot;http://geomobldn.org/&quot;&gt;#geomob&lt;/a&gt; over the last years. The obvious point is that with the rise of smart phones geo and location based services have now become the norm in everyone’s life - rich and poor, young and old. As a consequence, the key differentiatior of success and failure is increasingly NOT technical perfection and feature completeness, but rather usability. Simple wins, a lesson it is often easy for developers to forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My talk is below, let me know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;speakerdeck-embed&quot; data-id=&quot;8fa76f07490e41eb9b03130ccfb0d855&quot; data-ratio=&quot;1.33333333333333&quot; src=&quot;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 14:22:58 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/144851440100/my-jornadas-sig-libre-siglibre10-talk</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/144851440100/my-jornadas-sig-libre-siglibre10-talk</guid>
        
        
        <category>events,</category>
        
        <category>speaking,</category>
        
        <category>jornadasSIGlibre,</category>
        
        <category>siglibre10</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving the blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to move this blog off of tumblr and onto something I control more directly, probably also with a better front page on freyfogle.com that gives a bit more background about me and what I’m up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Partially I’m frustrated with tumblr’s tools (particularly the way it tries to “help” with formatting), partially I’m worried about tumblr’s future as parent-company yahoo sells, but most of all I want to create a better first impression for my digital identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does anyone have any recommendations (do not say wordpress, I hate wordpress). Right now I’m leaning toward &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; as it is plain text, which I can relate to.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 19:24:36 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/143741854375/moving-the-blog</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/143741854375/moving-the-blog</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thoughts on the UK Euro referendum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks back, on the 21st of Februrary to be exact, the UK government announced there will be a referendum about leaving the EU. Though I no longer live in the UK, I write these thoughts on the referendum as an EU citizen who spent the last 10 years living there, my two children were born there, and a few years ago my wife got UK citizenship.  While in the UK I (with another non-UK EU citizen) started a company that received foreign investment, employed and trained about 60 people (over the course of the 10 years, not all at once), and built a small, but global, business. I have paid my fair share of tax - and far more than any person’s fair share of rent - in the UK, I experienced the pleasure and pain of the NHS, I celebrated the Queen’s jubilee, I am an investor in about 10 different UK businesses, etc. I of course don’t have the chance to vote in the referendum, but nevertheless wanted to briefly express my view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the frustrations with the discussion around a big decision like the referendum (or the Scottish referendum the year before, or the discussion about Catalan independence here in Barcelona) is that both sides produce all sorts of numbers to argue their case, and it is utterly impossible for the layman to know what to believe. There is endless discussion and debates about various “facts”, most of it entirely unprovable. For the record, I do believe leaving the EU would be bad for the UK economically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me though, the date of the announcement of the referendum served as a great reminder of why we need the EU and why you should vote to stay in. February 23, 2016 was the 100th anniversary of the start of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Verdun&quot;&gt;battle of Verdun&lt;/a&gt;, one of the most brutal battles in human history, with close to a million casualties. In the UK, Verdun, because the battle featured Germans versus French, is overshadowed &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_the_Somme&quot;&gt;by the Somme&lt;/a&gt;, as a metaphore for senseless loss of life. Historians no doubt have a many a drunked argument about which was worse, but no doubt they were all horrific, as were many, many other battles in which Europeans killed other Europeans. I spent part of my childhood in Germany, growing up not that far away, and had the chance to visit Verdun a few times. If you can you should go, there is no other way to comprehend the utter scale of it. Even today huge stretches are still fenced off as they are too full of bombs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/verdun.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cathedral like building in this picture is one of many memorials in Verdun. It is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Douaumont_Ossuary&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Beinhaus von Douaumont&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, it contains the remains of 130,000 people. Think about that for a sec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re very fortunate that most modern Europeans never had to live through a catastrophic war, and we forget that it used to be totally normal for there to be a massive war between European countries once a generation. Or that the country I now live in, Spain, was a dictatorship in living memory, and indeed most of eastern Europe much more recently than that.
That is why we need the EU, and why we all need to be in it and continually working to improve it. So we don’t drift apart and fight, but rather so we work together to improve. The temptation to slide back into “us vs. them” thinking is always there - as we see most recently with Trump in the US, or many other examples. Working together is hard work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people, especially in the UK - but by no means only there, like to criticize the EU. Fair enough, that is their right. But we also shouldn’t forget what amazing progress has been made only in the last 30 years. Not only should we not forget it, we should celebrate it wildly, especially when we look at where we were only 100 years ago. More needs to be done to make the democracy in the EU more transparent, and probably many of the current systems and ways of working will need to change. The same was the case when the US started, and indeed any participatory government is always going to be a work in progress. So let’s do that work. But let’s not drift apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have the chance to vote in the referendum, please vote to stay. Let’s work together to create the EU we want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW - if you want to learn more about Verdun and WWI in general I highly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dancarlin.com/hardcore-history-series/&quot;&gt;Dan Carlin’s Hard Core History podcasts on the topic&lt;/a&gt;. They have been a great treat for me over the last few weeks.
Foto by &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=47593127&quot;&gt;Leon petrosyan - Own work, CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks Leon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 16:29:51 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/142627086455/thoughts-on-the-uk-euro-referendum</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/142627086455/thoughts-on-the-uk-euro-referendum</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Speaking at Jornadas SIG libre</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m delighted to announce I’ve been invited to speak at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sigte.udg.edu/jornadassiglibre/&quot;&gt;Jornadas SIG libre conference&lt;/a&gt; in Girona at the end of May. The event is the Spanish FOSS4G, the main conference about free and open source geospatial software.
I’m starting to think about what I might have to say that would be relevant to the audience, if you have any suggestions please let me know. Right now I’m thinking I’ll primarily focus on the trends I’ve seen in running &lt;a href=&quot;http://geomobldn.org/&quot;&gt;#geomob&lt;/a&gt; over the last six years, the lessons learned in running the &lt;a href=&quot;https://geocoder.opencagedata.com/&quot;&gt;OpenCage Geocoder&lt;/a&gt;, and  thoughts on investing in geo startups like &lt;a href=&quot;http://what3words.com/&quot;&gt;What3Words&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.splash-maps.com/&quot;&gt;SplashMaps&lt;/a&gt;.  
It should be a great event, and I’m looking forward to it as I’ve never been to Girona which everyone says is great. The language of the conference is Spanish, but I think to make any sort of meaningful presentation my talk will have to be in English.
Final thing: if geo events are your thing &lt;a href=&quot;http://geomobldn.org/post/139352132255/see-you-on-the-15th-of-march&quot;&gt;the next #geomob is on 15th of March&lt;/a&gt;, come along if you’re in London.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 11:55:45 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/139962599485/speaking-at-jornadas-sig-libre</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/139962599485/speaking-at-jornadas-sig-libre</guid>
        
        
        <category>jornadasSIGlibre,</category>
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Joining the board of MyBuilder</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last months many people have gotten in touch asking what I’m up to professionally since leaving Lokku. I’m exploring a number of different things, one that I’m pleased to now be able to announce is joining the board of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mybuilder.com/&quot;&gt;MyBuilder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;figure data-orig-width=&quot;1135&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;733&quot; class=&quot;tmblr-full&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img data-orig-width=&quot;1135&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;733&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/540.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those unfamiliar with the service, MyBuilder is a UK based marketplace where homeowners can find quality tradesmen. Whether you need a plumber, want to redo the kitchen, put solar panels on the roof, or whatever, MyBuilder helps you quickly and easily find and compare reputable tradesmen to get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve known the MyBuilder team for many years, in some ways the story is not unlike my own - an American founder who came to the UK and started a company around 2005. They are based in Clerkenwell, just as we were. 
Like our own journey with Lokku, it has been one of perseverance. Ryan Notz, the CEO and founder, and his team have tenaciously grown the business over the years. One thing that has really impressed me, and the reason I decided to get involved, is that they are focused on truly helping the homeowner solve the problem of repairing their home. What I mean is, many players in this space just flog leads out to anyone with an email address who is willing to buy them. MyBuilder takes a much deeper, more comprehensive approach. First, tradesmen who want to join the marketplace undergo an identity check AND a thorough test of their skills for the specific category they are interested in. They can not just say “I’m happy to do plumbing, wiring, masonry, gas fitting, really whatever anyone will pay me to do”. Secondly, the job is not simply spammed out to any and every tradesmen. If you want your kitchen redone that’s a big task with lots of decision to be made, the last thing you want to do is to first have to sift through hundreds of possible tradesmen. Instead, what you want is a short list of a handful of reputable, qualified, and available contractors, and that is exactly what MyBuilder provides. As you would expect, you can see reviews and ratings of their past work. It’s an approach that helps the homeowner solve the real task, not just a quick way to sell a lead, which is what many of MyBuilder’s competitors (who have come and gone over the years) have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equally important to Ryan and the management team though is creating a great culture within the team. &lt;a href=&quot;http://careers.mybuilder.com/&quot;&gt;They are hiring for a bunch of roles&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to work with great people building a great service, one that helps thousands of consumers and tradesmen every month, I can not think of a better company for you to join. The spirit of pride in the service is noticeable in everyone you talk with, and just like the tradesmen they aim to serve, there is a great sense of craftsmanship in the product side of the business. If you are interested in a product or tech role, have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.mybuilder.com/&quot;&gt;their tech blog&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mybuilder/&quot;&gt;code they have open-sourced&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This thoughtful approach is not always quick, but it is solid and it is paying off. The business is thriving. 2015 was a record year, and 2016 should be even better. More and more tradesmen are signing up, and the percentage of jobs posted by repeat users of the service is quite simply amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of that isn’t to say there are not challenges ahead for MyBuilder. The path from start-up to scale-up, from 5 team members to 50+, and then 200+, is not a simple one. Likewise, providing a high quality service raises customer expectations, and those expectations need to be continually met and exceeded. As MyBuilder moves out of the start-up phase of life and increasingly becomes a household name, I’m hopeful my own experiences and perspective can help on their journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 15:19:21 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/139847718265/joining-the-board-of-mybuilder</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/139847718265/joining-the-board-of-mybuilder</guid>
        
        
        <category>mybuilder</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>co-working life</title>
        <description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;figure data-orig-width=&quot;720&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;960&quot; class=&quot;tmblr-full&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img data-orig-width=&quot;720&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;960&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/540.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend was kind enough to invite me along to visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.betahaus.es/&quot;&gt;Betahaus Barcelona&lt;/a&gt; for a day this week. Unbeknownst to me they snapped this pic of me hard at work and are now using it on their FB feed. Might this be the big break that finally lands me in the pages of Monocle?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 22:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/139617318635/co-working-life</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/139617318635/co-working-life</guid>
        
        
        <category>betahaus,</category>
        
        <category>workinghardorhardlyworking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Steady progress on mapping the new neighborhood</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freyfogle.com/post/138272982085/goals-for-2016&quot;&gt;my goals for 2016&lt;/a&gt; was to map the new neighbourhood as a way to get to know what is where. I’m making slow but steady progress, and it’s been a good refresh. Years of living in central London, which is mapped in amazing detail, made it hard to find new things to map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;figure data-orig-width=&quot;1670&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;1038&quot; class=&quot;tmblr-full&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img data-orig-width=&quot;1670&quot; data-orig-height=&quot;1038&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/540.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been focusing on addresses mainly, though have also found and corrected several bad roads, missing names of parks, etc. My technique has mainly been pen and paper and then edit on the desktop, though in the last few days I’ve been experimenting with using &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Go_Map!!&quot;&gt;the Go Map!! app&lt;/a&gt; on my iphone. It’s ok for adding addresses, though the limited screen space makes it hard to do much more. A very challenging usability problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway I should have the addresses for my main radius of action done in a few weeks, and am debating what to then focus on. It’s been a fun experiment and helped me learn the new neighbourhood. I recommend it if you move somewhere new.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 13:43:16 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://freyfogle.com/post/139479274255/steady-progress-on-mapping-the-new-neighborhood</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://freyfogle.com/post/139479274255/steady-progress-on-mapping-the-new-neighborhood</guid>
        
        
        <category>openstreetmap</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
